<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jiayi Ji on Jiayi Ji</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jiayi Ji on Jiayi Ji</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Jiayi Ji</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Management</title>
      <link>/post/time-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/time-management/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-self-analysis&#34;&gt;My self-analysis&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the rock-hard truth as a result of self-analysis of my life so far:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am lazy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, that&amp;rsquo;s my weakness rooted in my genes, kind like the animal behaviours driven by genetics rather than rational, logical decisions by my brain. Can&amp;rsquo;t deny it. Here is a list:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I prefer to stay in my comfort zone (like being single 😞);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have also filled my to-do list on Gist or wunderlust, and didn&amp;rsquo;t finish them;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have interests in a lot of things, then passion fades away and I turn to new things;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I will first exhaust the interesting videos on Bilibili beforing starting to do my work;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is there any updates on my favourite sports teams and players? Let me check it out first;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My record for The Legend of Heroes series reached 1000+ hrs. My, my, my&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I wonder how I have not been ruled out by the law of evolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-leads-to-this&#34;&gt;What Leads to This&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The traditional education, culture and beliefs shared among Chinese value hard-working as a virtue. I identify myself sharing these values, and I really feel guilty being lazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I&amp;rsquo;m also influenced by other perspectives and by my personal experiences as well, which partly changed my view on hard-working in an unnoticed way, at least that&amp;rsquo;s what I thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;personal-experience&#34;&gt;Personal Experience&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, since the first day attending the school, I don&amp;rsquo;t find it difficult to be one of the top students in most subjects without much effort. This might lead to the idea that being smart is an advantage I could take to compensate for the efforts I didn&amp;rsquo;t pay as others did. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have much failures during my student days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as over-protected organisms will be more sensitive to infections, failures or obstacles strike harder on me when they come. When I was fortunate enough (long story short here) to enter Fudan University, which is among top three university in China, I find it difficult to survive by continuing taking advantage of my little wit and not taking much effort. This is because my classmates are all smart like hell. Different from the high school where a stringent and established system that can push you foward, the life in university is more about self-management which I was not good at.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:I-am-not-as-well&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:I-am-not-as-well&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; As a result, my studies were not so good in the first year (GPA 2.98, I vividly remember). Later I slowly accepted this, put some effort in it, and finally ended now at Columbia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until now, it might become a habit of me to utilize my small wit for not working hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;misintepreted-readings&#34;&gt;Misintepreted Readings&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, I read a lot when I could. I ran into multiple interesting articles arguing that being lazy is a virtue, because:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most inventions came into being because the inventors&amp;rsquo; initial motive is to save time and effort.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In order to save time for being lazy, smart people tend to use innovative ways to solve problems and do the work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, that convinced me to keep being lazy. But it turned out I confused this type of lazy with procrastinating, which is just doing-nothing-to-evade-real-life-problems kind of lazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;beliefs&#34;&gt;Beliefs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, It&amp;rsquo;s more of a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Existential_crisis&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;existential crisis&lt;/a&gt; of mine in my early 20s, wondering if anything has a meaning. Humans cannot choose whether to enter this world, and cannot choose whether to exit this world as well. A thought like this could make me depressed sometimes, which further leads to a questioning of the meaning of what I have done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My statistics training at Columbia gives me a conception that
there always exists some sense of randomness for which I don&amp;rsquo;t have any control. My undergradute major in medicine also leads to my acknowlodgement that our brain is easily affected by hormones and all the emotions, motivations, ambitions, decisions, love and personalities are affected by them. In short, most things we do are to serve the reward circuit in our brain in exchange for some dopamine, in another word, happiness. &lt;del&gt;So why not just enjoy being lazy?&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-to-do-about-my-laziness&#34;&gt;What to Do About My Laziness&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many instructions out in the wild. But I doubt their effiacy. Maybe the biggest difficulty is to take better control of myself, I&amp;rsquo;ll list a few:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do regular exercises.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do the honest work I&amp;rsquo;m supposed to do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fuck it, I&amp;rsquo;m doing what I want to do and get paid for it, what else should I expect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;is-life-really-just-random&#34;&gt;Is life REALLY just&amp;hellip;random?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://assets.amuniversal.com/321a39e06d6401301d80001dd8b71c47&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;comic from &lt;a href=&#34;http://dilbert.com/strip/2001-10-25&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;xkcd&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:I-am-not-as-well&#34;&gt;I am not as well, currently &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:I-am-not-as-well&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quote</title>
      <link>/quote/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/quote/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am not a computer scientist. I am a social scientist who uses programming and computational tools to answer my research questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of this course is to teach you basic computational skills and provide you with the means to learn what you need to know for your own research. I start from the perspective that you want to analyze data, and programming is a means to that end. You will not become an expert programmer - that is a given. But you will learn the basic skills and techniques necessary to conduct computational social science, and gain the confidence necessary to learn new techniques as you encounter them in your research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The skill is in breaking up a problem into smaller parts until each part is simple enough to be computed using these basic instructions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comments are the what - what is the program doing? Code is the how - how is the program going to do this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href=&#34;http://cfss.uchicago.edu/block001_intro.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://cfss.uchicago.edu/block001_intro.html&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why setup your R projects this way? There’s a big advantage to the “Github first, then RStudio”&amp;rdquo; workflow: the remote GitHub repo is now the “upstream” remote for your local repo. In essence, you are already setup to push and pull commits to GitHub. There is no need to set anything else up through the shell or a Git client.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://cfss.uchicago.edu/git05.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://cfss.uchicago.edu/git05.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Search of Lost Time: 2017</title>
      <link>/post/in-search-of-lost-time-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/in-search-of-lost-time-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2017 will gone, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t even have time to write one single blog post. An obvious inference should be, 2017 doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist&amp;hellip; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2017 was a year of struggle for me as a biostatistics master student. I spent most time at school learning statistical theories, which sometimes drove me nuts as I came from pure medical background. I do achieve excellent grades (straight A+) for my courses. But, are the proofs and derivations useful for my future career? It is not a silly question. Lots of my peers also feel the crunch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, in 2017, I&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;learned some &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.datacamp.com/profile/11307120163&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;read &lt;a href=&#34;http://r4ds.had.co.nz/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;R for Data Science&lt;/a&gt; from cover to cover 3 times,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;employed tidyverse packages for my projects (&lt;code&gt;ggplot&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;dplyr&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;purrr&lt;/code&gt; for analysis and &lt;code&gt;R Markdown&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;xaringan&lt;/code&gt; for communication),&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;learned some concepts of machine learning through the &lt;a href=&#34;https://lagunita.stanford.edu/courses/HumanitiesSciences/StatLearning/Winter2016/about&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;online courses&lt;/a&gt; and the reader-friendly &lt;a href=&#34;http://www-bcf.usc.edu/~gareth/ISL/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;textbook&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;learned some more concepts of machine learning through the classic &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.stanford.edu/~hastie/ElemStatLearn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;textbook&lt;/a&gt; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;didn&amp;rsquo;t write one single blog post, because all my spare time and coffee making time were simply run out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel much better after one year of burying my head in the sand. Keep tuned, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Jiayi’s website</title>
      <link>/post/welcome-to-jiayi-s-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/welcome-to-jiayi-s-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, you want start a personal website? And you are also an R user? Then the R package &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rstudio/blogdown&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;blogdown&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is the best (state-of-the-art) way to create a static website that is generated using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rstudio.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;RStudio&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My website is powered by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;academic&lt;/a&gt; theme for &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;, a perfect theme for personal or academic websites, and is hosted on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.netlify.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Netlify&lt;/a&gt;. For more details on how to build the website through the awesome &lt;code&gt;blogdown&lt;/code&gt; R package, please check out my step-by-step tutorial in my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/JiayiJi/JiayiJi&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;github repository&lt;/a&gt;. Feel free to contact me if you have questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will primarily use the website to share my projects and publications, as well as posts mostly related to data science and biostatistics.
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;New blog post: &amp;quot;Advice to aspiring data scientists: start a blog&amp;quot; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/yMDHqviiBN&#34;&gt;https://t.co/yMDHqviiBN&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/rstats?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#rstats&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/9AdPUdbjtE&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/9AdPUdbjtE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; David Robinson (@drob) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/drob/status/930492543187513345?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;November 14, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

As an aspiring data scientist, now it&amp;rsquo;s time to blog!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estimating Influenza Incidence from Diagnostic Codes</title>
      <link>/publication/flu_final_project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/flu_final_project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is my paper for final project for Fall 2017 course: P9120 Topics in Statistical Learning &amp;amp; Data Mining taught by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mailman.columbia.edu/people/our-faculty/mq2158&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Min Qian&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identifying melanoma prognostic biomarkers by integrating imaging data and genetic data</title>
      <link>/project/melanoma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/melanoma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am conducting research with &lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.google.com/view/ligen&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Gen Li&lt;/a&gt; at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mailman.columbia.edu/become-student/departments/biostatistics&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Department of Biostatistics at Columbia University&lt;/a&gt;, Yvonne Saenger and Robyn Gartrell from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cumc.columbia.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Columbia University Medical Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My work involved:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating interactive heat maps and adopting clustering analysis to explore hierarchical structure of melanoma gene expression data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Building predictive model on recurrence using logistic regression with lasso penalty, and validated it on two separate cohorts using cross-validation with bootstrapping.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Communicating results of analyses, modeling, and tests through data visualization, interactive apps, and writing in R Markdown.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paper in progress.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detecting Gender Salary Discrimination Using Multiple Regression</title>
      <link>/publication/linear_regression_project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/linear_regression_project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is my final paper for the final project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detecting Gender Salary Discrimination Using Multiple Regression</title>
      <link>/project/linear_regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/linear_regression/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This is my final project for Spring 2017 course: &lt;a href=&#34;http://jeffgoldsmith.com/P8111/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;P8111 Linear Regression Models&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I assessed the relationship between gender and salary using a case from the United States District Court of Houston. Several multiple regression models were conducted and yielded convergent finding: male and female doctors were equivalently paid taking account of other productivity-related attributes. While these results should be reassuring, they would not go very far toward resolving salary discrimination disputes. The difficulties of employing statistical analyses within a politically-charged arena are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;additional-resources&#34;&gt;Additional Resources&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/pdf/P8111_Final_Project.pdf&#34;&gt;Final Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/JiayiJi/P8111-Final-Project/tree/master&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Source Code and Dataset&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;date&#34;&gt;Date&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2017-05-06&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ZooRisk</title>
      <link>/project/pnnl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/pnnl/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In the summer of 2017, I interned at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pnnl.gov/nationalsecurity/technical/capabilities/computing/data_sciences.stm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Data Sciences &amp;amp; Analytics Group&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pnnl.gov/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Pacific Northwest National Laboratory&lt;/a&gt;. I collaborated with designers and programmers to produce a bio-surveillance web application, which will give real-time risk assessment for each news related to zoonotic diseases. My mentor is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pnnl.gov/science/staff/staff_info.asp?staff_num=8834&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Lauren Charles&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;thanks-img-internship-background-jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/Internship_background.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Thanks&#34; /&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;additional-resources&#34;&gt;Additional Resources&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The following video gives a short introduction to our final web application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/Qy3B3xc1Z7A&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34; title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jiayiji.github.io/PNNL-Experience/Slide.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Slide&lt;/a&gt;: I was invited by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mailman.columbia.edu/people/current-students/student-life/student-groups#CCC&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Career China Club&lt;/a&gt; at Columbia University Mailman School of Public Health to share my experience at PNNL. This is the slide for my talk.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Latent Growth Analysis of Repeated Measures Blood Pressure Data</title>
      <link>/project/latent_variable/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/latent_variable/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This is my final project for Spring 2017 course: P8158 Latent Variable and Structural Equation Modeling for Health Sciences taught by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.columbia.edu/~mmw2177/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Melanie M. Wall&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uncontrolled hypertension can lead to serious health problems, including heart attack and stroke. Our data comes from the masked hypertension study, which collected ambulatory blood pressure data and measured physical activity using accelerometers in order to better understand what factors contribute to high blood pressure. We used latent growth curve modeling to analyze the data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;additional-resources&#34;&gt;Additional Resources&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/pdf/P8158_Final_Project.pdf&#34;&gt;Final Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/pdf/LV_presentation.pdf&#34;&gt;Slide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;date&#34;&gt;Date&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2017-04-22&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Latent Growth Analysis of Repeated Measures Blood Pressure Data</title>
      <link>/publication/latent_variable_project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/latent_variable_project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is our paper for the final project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects of school breaks on influenza-like illness incidence in a temperate Chinese region: an ecological study from 2008 to 2015</title>
      <link>/publication/bmj_open/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/bmj_open/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;OBJECTIVE: To assess the effects of winter/summer school breaks on occurrences of influenza-like illness (ILI).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;METHODS: We jointly analysed ILI surveillance data with the timing of school breaks in a temperate district in Beijing, China from 2008 to 2015. ILI incidence rate ratios (IRRs) of schoolchildren (5–14 and 15–24 years of age) to adults (25–59 and &amp;gt;60 years of age) were used to measure the age shift of ILI incidence before, during and after the 4-week winter/7-week summer breaks. Serfling-based Poisson regression model with adjustment for unmeasured confounders was built to further assess the effect of winter school breaks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RESULTS: ILI incidences were consistently lower during winter breaks than before winter breaks for all age groups. IRRs of younger schoolchildren aged 5–14 to adults were higher during winter school breaks than before breaks, while the opposite was true for the IRRs of older schoolchildren aged 15–24 to adults. Schoolchildren-to-adults IRRs during summer breaks were significantly lower than before or after school breaks (p&amp;lt;0.001).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CONCLUSIONS: Both winter and summer breaks were associated with reductions of ILI incidences among schoolchildren and adults. Our study contributes additional evidence on the effects of school breaks on ILI incidence, suggesting school closure could be effective in controlling influenza transmission in developing countries.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Latent Growth Analysis of Repeated Measures Blood Pressure Data</title>
      <link>/talk/latent_variable_slide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/latent_variable_slide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the slide for my my final project presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Final</title>
      <link>/talk/pnnl_slide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/pnnl_slide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My principal contributions to team effort includes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search and read the literature about animal disease and risk assessment for it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn different statistical methods about risk assessment for animal health.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Communicate the methods to our teammates and lead the discussions to decide which methods to use for our app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Translate the statistical methods to python codes to help Jacob write the codes more efficiently.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compile and write the documentation of our app to help our teammates understand the big picture of our app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predict Flu Incidence from Diagnostic Codes</title>
      <link>/talk/flu_slide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/flu_slide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is my slide for final project for Fall 2017 course: P9120 Topics in Statistical Learning &amp;amp; Data Mining taught by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mailman.columbia.edu/people/our-faculty/mq2158&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Min Qian&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
